# RODRIGO SOUSA MARQUES

## Data Scientist | Data Engineer

Experienced Data Scientist and Data Enginer. Skilled in Data Science, Business Intelligence, Data Analytics, Power BI, SQL, Python, DAX, Machine Learning, ETL, Snowflake, DBT, GIT, among others. I can say that I'm curious by nature and always thrilled to challenge "unsolvable problems", an out-ofthe-box thinker who loves to create and explore new ideas and perspectives. Someone who knows when and how to adapt to keep evolving. I've found in Data Science the perfect environment to do what I love be: be challenged and learn everyday. Fluent in English and Portuguese and basic French and Spanish.

marques.tech@gmail.com



+54 11 7897.6313



Buenos Aires, Argentina



in linkedin.com/in/rmargues0

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Scientist**

Pistil Data

08/2021 - Present

San Francisco - CA USA

- Responsible to produce high-quality code for the existing projects and new ones to support the customer and business team to improve the platform.
- Collaborate closely with the technical team to integrate and productionize data science deliverable (e.g. models, data output, data quality).
- Python (Pandas, Scikit Learn, Scipy, Seaborn, SQLAlchemy, df2gspread, Plotly, Matplotlib, etc), SQL, Git, Azure data studio, GSuite, Hubspot.

# **Data Engineer**

Cloud(x):

02/2022 - Present

Buenos Aires - Argentina

• Currently as a contractor to Symend . Symend generates deep customer insights using a trifecta of behavioral science, data science, and advanced analytics to empower customers to resolve past due bills before they reach collections

### **Data Consultant**

wDiscover

11/2020 - Present

Pinhais - PR Brazil

• Project for Ouro Verde which consisted of Legacy system migration to AWS. Redshift, EMR, Athena, Batch, Step Functions, Elastic Container Registry, S3, EC2, CloudWatch

# **Data Science & Business Intelligence Analyst**

TKSolution | Tok&Stok

08/2020 - 08/2021

São Paulo - SP, Brazil

- I tackled Data Science and Business Intelligence challenges driving intelligence, strategy, innovation, and valuable solutions.
- Developed of intelligent cubes (SSAS); Managerial Reports (Power BI and Reporting Services - Back and Front-end); Data governance management and dealt with data extraction and manipularion on Oracle/Snowflake/Web/APIs.
- SQL, PL/SQL, Python, DAX, M.Power Bi, DBT, SSMS, SSAS, SSRS, Git, Oracle, Snowflake, Gsuite, Jira, Confluence, AWS (Glue, S3, Database Migration Service, Cloudwatch).

# **EDUCATION**

# MBA in Business Intelligence

UNIMAIS - Faculdade Educamais

01/2020 - 01/2021

**Brazil** 

## **Electrical Engineering BS**

UniCatólica - Centro Universitário Católica do Tocantins

07/2016 - 12/2019 Palmas - TO, Brazil

# **SKILLS**

Python, PL / SQL, DAX, M, Git, Unix dash

Data Science, Analytics, Power BI, DataViz

Data Engineering, Snowflake, DBT, ETL

Leadership, Teamwork, Lean Six Sigma, Agile

Critical, Creative and Adaptive Thinking

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Awarded with exchange program in USA (09/2014 - 12/2015)

Sponsored by CAPES/CNPq as a top student of Universidade Federal do Tocantins. Sandwich undergraduation in Electrical Engineering at Eastern Washington University, WA.

## Summer Internship in Lean Enterprise Systems - University of Tennessee (06/2015 - 07/2015)

Project implemented at Comercial Vehicle Group (CVG): Reduced waiting time by 10.79% in CVG's testing lab; Solved the problems of management processes, mitigating rework;

#### Publication on Brazilian Journal of Development 2

Intelligent Access and Electronics Control using Microcontroller ATMEGA238P Seeking for Energy Efficiency -Brazilian Journal of Development, v.6,n. 8, p. 63859-63867 -Qualis B2 Magazine

## **CERTIFICATES**

Snowflake - The Complete Masterclass

Unified Data Essentials

Databricks

Deploying Scalable ML for Data Science

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Udemy

Business Analysis Foundations

International Institute of Business Analysis

C2 Proficient English - Standard English Test EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

Lean Enterprise Systems Program

University of Tennessee